Jacob D. Ulmer

6624 Belcrest Drive Barnhart, Missouri 63012 (314) 591-2219 jakeulmer2@yahoo.com

Over the past 7 years with Drury Hotels, I have demonstrated my ability to listen and respond to customer needs, to work well with internal and external partners and to communicate to variety of audiences. In my most recent role, I have shown a high level of attention to detail and analytical thinking, while providing leadership with meaningful interpretations of the data.

While partnering with our IT team to develop reporting capabilities, I discovered my interest in gaining a better understanding of the systems we use. I have become passionate about the field of computer programming and its infinite possibilities. I intend to continue advancing my knowledge and skills in hopes of launching a new career in this field.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Drury Hotels Company, LLC.

St. Louis, Missouri

July 2010-Present

- National Sales Specialist
 - Assist managers with supervisory duties including the review and approval of exceptions to normal booking procedures.
 - Analyze departmental data to:
 - Identify errors
 - Recognize training opportunities
 - Recommend best practices
 - o Forecast sales
 - Work with IT and Sales Managers to create, maintain and update relevant reports.
- National Sales Coordinator
 - Received high ratings on customer service surveys, resulting in returning business and recommendations for the company.
 - Used attention to detail, organization skills, and teamwork to complete data entry in timely manner to best fill the customers' requests.
 - Worked together with Regional and Area Sales Managers to book group business, and be attentive to each customer's specific needs.
 - Communicated via email and telephone with customers daily to help maximize their experience and the company's profits.

Vogel Brothers Painting LLC.

St. Louis, Missouri

May 2006-June 2010

May-August, 2004 and 2005

- Residential and Commercial Painter
 - Gained teamwork, leadership, and organizational skills by guiding team efforts to complete jobs in a timely manner and exceed expectations.

Prudential Select Properties

St. Charles and Imperial, Missouri

July 2006-September 2008

- Real Estate Sales Consultant
 - O Developed face-to-face sales skills through meeting with walk-in clients, and holding open houses.
 - Expanded administration skills by preparing contracts and establishing computerized notifications for clients.

EDUCATION

LaunchCode, St. Louis, Missouri

- LC101 Certificate in Java and Python, December 2017
- o Intensive, 20-week program designed to train students with skills to seek a career in technology Career Education Systems, Inc., St. Louis, Missouri
 - Licensed Real Estate Professional under Missouri Real Estate Commission, July 2006
- Webster University, St. Louis, Missouri
 - Bachelor of Science in Business Administration, May 2006